A Guide to the Reeves family Records, 1850-1905
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Reeves family Records, 1850-1905
Library of Virginia
26769
1.35 cu. ft. (3 boxes and 1 oversize folder)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of William R. Dunn, Lynchburg, Virginia, June 1967.
Biographical/Historical Information
Isaac J. Reeves (1819-1892) was a farmer in South Boston, Halifax County, Virginia. He also owned a blacksmith shop and was a partner in Blount and Reeves, wheelwrights. He was married to Lucy M. Reeves (1823- 1901). Their son, William T. Reeves (1861-1933) was a pharmacist in South Boston.
Scope and Content
Records, 1850-1905, of the Reeves family of South Boston, Halifax County, Virginia. Included are accounts and receipts, broadsides, catalogs and price lists, correspondence, deeds, ledgers, memorandum books, publications, and reports. The records mainly relate to Isaac J. Reeves, a farmer and wheelwright, and his son, William T. Reeves, a pharmacist in South Boston, Virginia.
Included are accounts and receipts, 1858-1901, for insurance, wagon repairs, hardware, and groceries from stores in Danville, Richmond, and South Boston, Virginia. Also included is a deed and survey for land in South Boston and several memorandum books. Publications relating to the Temperance movement, Grand Lodge Knights of Pythias of Virginia, Republican Party, and the Independent Order of Good Templars are also included.
Of note are the advertisement cards, broadsides, catalogs and price lists from companies in South Boston, Danville, and Richmond, Virginia. The catalogs and price lists are divided into categories: agriculture, machinery and carriages, medical supplies, music and art supplies, and religious. The musical catalogs were used to purchase a new organ for the Methodist Church in South Boston. The catalogs are of note because they document many companies which are no longer extant in Virginia. Some of the companies include: Allison & Addison (Richmond, Va.); A.B. Clarke (Richmond, Va.); Edwards, Noblin & Co. (S. Boston, Va.); G.E. Faulkner (S. Boston, Va.); Frank Tobacco Co. (Danville, Va.); Greensboro Handle Works (Greensboro, NC); Louisville Hub, Spoke and Wheel (Louisville, KY); James McGraw (Richmond, Va.); Old Dominion Iron and Nail Works (Richmond, Va.); Simpson & Brothers (Richmond, Va.); and G.F. Watson Furniture Works (Richmond, Va.). Also included are various "get rich quick" flyers in the oversize folder.
The ledgers include account books for Blount and Reeves, wheelwrights; personal ledgers of Isaac J. Reeves; an account book of Sons of Temperance, Falmouth Division No. 388; a railway freight account book; and Salem church Sunday school records. Also of note are drawings of several South Boston homes and businesses by an unknown artist.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Contents List
- Abstinance oath, c. 1896 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Accounts and receipts, 1858-1869 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Accounts and receipts, 1870-1879 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Accounts and receipts, 1880-1889 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Accounts and receipts, 1890-1898 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Accounts and receipts, 1900-1901 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Accounts and receipts, nd (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Advertisements cards, c. 1890-1900 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Arrington Brothers, Grocers (Danville, Va.)
  Peter Bilhorn, Publisher (Chicago, IL)
  Brown, Weld & Co., Spoke manufacturer (Charlotte County, Va.)
  Edward Noblin & Co., Druggists (South Boston, Va.)
  Eureka Soap Co. (Cincinnati, OH)
  Faulkner, Owen & Co., Livery stable (South Boston, Va.)
  Frank Tobacco Co. (Danville, Va.)
  C.W. Harvey & Son, Wagons (Danville, Va.)
  Hickety & Sublett, Hardware dealer (Danville, Va.)
  S. Jablonski & Co., General merchandise (South Boston, Va.)
  Martin & Mason, Commission mechants (Richmond, Va.)
  Martin & Cardozo, Commission merchants (Richmond, Va.)
  James McGraw, Hardware dealer (Richmond, Va.)
  R.W. Powers & Co., Druggists (Richmond, Va.)
  W.R. Pugh, Merchant (Richmond, Va.)
- Barbour Buggy Co. (South Boston, Va.), 1890 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Broadsides, 1878-1892 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Catalogs and prices lists, Agriculture, c. 1876 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Allison & Addison, Dealers in seeds and fertilizers (Richmond, Va.)
- Catalogs and prices lists, Machinery and carriages, c. 1870-1900 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  D.J. Baldwin, Hardware and carriages (Richmond, Va.)
  C.E. Bennett, Carts (Jackson, MI)
  "The Blacksmith's Journal", Day Bros. (Philadelphia, Pa.)
  Cumberland, Dugan & Co., Carriages (Baltimore, MD)
  Douglas Manufacturing Co. (NY, NY)
  James McGraw, Machinists supplies (Richmond, Va.)
  Smith, Fulton & Rogers, Carriages (Louisville, KY)
- Catalogs and prices lists, Machinery and carriages, c. 1870-1900 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Burden Iron Works (Troy, NY)
  "The Carriage Maker's & Painter's Guide" by G.W. Clark
  Clark & Rousseau, Carriage and buggy ornaments (Buffalo, NY)
  C.W. Coe, Bolt cutter (Fenton, MI)
  G.F. Watson, Furniture works (Richmond, Va.)
  George O. Stevens & Co., Window sashes (Baltimore, MD)
  Greensboro Handle Works, Spokes (Greensboro, NC)
  Maryland Paint and Color Works (Baltimore, MD)
  North Carolina Coach Material Co., Spokes (Greensboro, NC)
  Simpson & Brothers, Carriages and wagons (Richmond, Va.)
  P.H. Starke, Plows (Richmond, Va.)
  E.B. Whitman, Fertilizers and plows (Baltimore, MD)
  Samuel G. Winternitz, Iron and steel warehouse (Baltimore, MD)
- Catalogs and prices lists, Medical supplies, c. 1870-1900 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Dr. J. Ball & Co.'s Patent Improved Ivory Eye Cups (NY, NY)
  Carr Brothers & Co., Wholesale druggists (Baltimore, MD)
  "Cyclopedia of Things Worth Knowing; Or, 25,000 Wants Supplied"
  Hance Brothers & White, Chemists (Philadelphia, Pa.)
  G.E. Faulkner, Druggist (S. Boston, Va.)
  Hamlins Wizard Oil Co., Directors for using Hamlins Wizard Oil (Chicago, IL)
  Kennedy & Co., Druggists (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  Dr. Pierce's Family Medicines (Buffalo, NY)
  Perry Davis & Son, Druggist (Providence, RI)
- Catalogs and price lists, Musical, c. 1870-1900 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Catalogs and price lists, Religious, c. 1870-1900 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Catalogs and price lists, Misc., c. 1870-1900 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Circular letters, 1871-1896 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1871-1879 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1880-1887 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1891-1898 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1900-1905 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, nd (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Deeds, 1872-1878 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Grand Lodge of Virginia, Independent Order of Odd Fellows, Certificates, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Invitations, 1892-1894 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Leases, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Medicinal cures, nd (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Memorandum books, 1872-1892 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Methodist Church (South Boston, Va.), Account, nd (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Oaths, 1869 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Order form, c. 1880 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Poetry, nd (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Publications, "Address of the Readjuster Members of the Legislature to the People!", Richmond, Virginia, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Publications, "Homes for the Homelss. What the Republican Party has done for the Poor Man," nd (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Publications, "Independent Order of Good Templars of North Carolina," 1873 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Publications, "Knights of Pythias," 1894-1898 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Publications, "Oskaloosa Power and Land Company," nd (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Publications, Play, "Josiah's Courtship," 1892 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Publications, "Proceedings of the Friends of Temperance," 1874-1875 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Publications, Religious, 1859-1872 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Publications, "Valley Mutual Life Association of Virginia (Staunton, Va.)," 1878 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Publications, "The Washington Life Insurance Company of New York," 1898 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- "South Boston, Virginia: The Country's Largest and Youngest Settlement," nd (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Stock certificates, 1891-1897 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Stories, nd (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Tax receipts, 1861-1893 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- United States Mutual Accident Association, Certificate, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Virginia State Insurance Company of Richmond, Report, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Ledgers, Blount and Reeves, 1878-1879 (Box 3)
- Ledgers, Blount and Reeves, 1882-1883 (Box 3)
- Ledgers, Blount and Reeves, 1884 (Box 3)
- Ledgers, Isaac J. Reeves, 1853-1860 (Box 3)
- Ledgers, Isaac J. Reeves, 1861-1862 (Box 3)
- Ledgers, Jacob I. Reeves, Railway freight account book, 1857-1859 (Box 3)
- Ledgers, Salem Sunday School, 1871-1872 (Box 3)
- Ledgers, Sons of Temperance, Falmouth Division No. 388, Treasury book, 1850-1862 (Box 3)
- Oversize broadsides and flyers, c. 1870-1900 (Oversize Oversize folder, includes sketches of South Boston)